<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cypress Synergy on Joshua E. Lambert, PhD</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/</link><description>Recent content in Cypress Synergy on Joshua E. Lambert, PhD</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Canine Behavior</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/canine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/canine/</guid><description>Cypress Synergy also provides solutions and mentorship regarding canine behavior. The services available are listed below.
As a free resource for dog handlers we provide the following working document:
A Working Resource for Life with Dogs
If you feel inclined to contribute to this document&amp;rsquo;s progress please contribute Here.
Services In-person mentorship for handler and canine Online consulting (including tailored video feedback) Extended puppy socialization and obedience training (3-4 week boarding in addition to handler mentorship)</description></item><item><title>Core Approach</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/core/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/core/</guid><description>The fundamental approach behind Cypress Synergy is to address each problem with an open mind set. Each case is different and rather than bringing in all the answers from experience, Cypress Synergy tries to incorporate new data with each iteration. In many ways the company itself functions as a learning algorithm would, getting better as it goes.
With that said, where Cypress Synergy sets itself apart is the broad range of tools it has to meet the customer&amp;rsquo;s particular needs.</description></item><item><title>Cypress Synergy, LLC</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/about/</guid><description>Joshua E. Lambert is the founder of Cypress Synergy, LLC. Cypress Synergy provides a wide range of services tailored specifically to the client. Joshua leverages his professional and educational experience to fit the problem set with the appropriate service.
To set up an initial consultation email here.
Toolkit: Problem identification and research design Data operationalization Statistical analysis Geographical information systems Advanced data visualization Machine Learning applications and forecasting Natural language processing Web scraping Canine behavioral mentorship Communication: Written reports Web applications Oral presentations Public lectures Private briefings Areas of expertise: Methodological applications Civil-military relations Contagion (social phenomena) Conflict processes Political behavior and psychology Canine behavior</description></item></channel></rss>