<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Joshua E. Lambert, PhD</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Joshua E. Lambert, PhD</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://JELambert.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Search Results</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ``` [outputs] home = [&amp;ldquo;HTML&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo;] ```</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/publications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/publications/</guid><description>Peer Reviewed Introducing the Commons Synthesis Project: Topics and trends in the study of common-pool resource. International Journal of the Commons (Forthcoming), Joshua E. Lambert, Graham Epstein, Jennifer Joel, and Jacopo Baggio.
Reassessing Private Military and Security Company (PMSC) &amp;lsquo;Competition&amp;rsquo; in Civil War: Lessons from Sierra Leone. Small Wars &amp;amp; Insurgencies (2019) - Issue 3, Christopher Faulkner, Joshua E. Lambert, and Jonathan Powell.
Dissertation Food, Familiarity, and Forecasting: Modeling Coups with Computational Methods.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/talks/</guid><description>2021 American Political Science Association Religious Pluralism and Mass Violence: A Global Analysis with Gunes Tezcur International Studies Association Annual Meeting (Virtual) Militarized Fisheries Conflicts Associated with Global Climate
with Cullen Hendrix, Sarah M. Glaser, and Paige Roberts Centre College Guest Lecture (IST 210 - Research Design) Overview of GIS in Empirical Social Science
UCF School of Politics, Security and International Affairs Colloquium The Commons Synthesis Project: Applying machine learning to synthesize knowledge on community-based natural resource management</description></item><item><title>Cypress Synergy, LLC</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/about/</guid><description>Joshua E. Lambert is the founder of Cypress Synergy, LLC. Cypress Synergy provides a wide range of services tailored specifically to the client. Joshua leverages his professional and educational experience to fit the problem set with the appropriate service.
To set up an initial consultation email here.
Toolkit: Problem identification and research design Data operationalization Statistical analysis Geographical information systems Advanced data visualization Machine Learning applications and forecasting Natural language processing Web scraping Canine behavioral mentorship Communication: Written reports Web applications Oral presentations Public lectures Private briefings Areas of expertise: Methodological applications Civil-military relations Contagion (social phenomena) Conflict processes Political behavior and psychology Canine behavior</description></item><item><title>Canine Behavior</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/canine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/canine/</guid><description>Cypress Synergy also provides solutions and mentorship regarding canine behavior. The services available are listed below.
As a free resource for dog handlers we provide the following working document:
A Working Resource for Life with Dogs
If you feel inclined to contribute to this document&amp;rsquo;s progress please contribute Here.
Services In-person mentorship for handler and canine Online consulting (including tailored video feedback) Extended puppy socialization and obedience training (3-4 week boarding in addition to handler mentorship)</description></item><item><title>Core Approach</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/core/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/cypress/core/</guid><description>The fundamental approach behind Cypress Synergy is to address each problem with an open mind set. Each case is different and rather than bringing in all the answers from experience, Cypress Synergy tries to incorporate new data with each iteration. In many ways the company itself functions as a learning algorithm would, getting better as it goes.
With that said, where Cypress Synergy sets itself apart is the broad range of tools it has to meet the customer&amp;rsquo;s particular needs.</description></item><item><title>Back Coup d'Future: An Ensemble Machine Learning Framework for Coups Prediction</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/forecast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/forecast/</guid><description>The quantitative study of coups has benefited from immense explanatory research, but less so with regard to prediction. I present a systematic framework for modeling coups utilizing a machine learning ensemble approach. Forecasts are assessed at the country level with yearly temporal resolutions. I outline a methodology that covers feature identification, processing and selection, model development and deployment, and finally metrics for assessing the predictive capacity. Forecasts indicate that in 2020 the five most likely countries for a military coup include Thailand, Tunisia, Somalia, Burundi and Ethiopia.</description></item><item><title>Coups and Innovation Diffusion</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/familiar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/familiar/</guid><description>Theoretically this paper makes an important contribution to the coup contagion scholarship by conceptualizing a more plausible pathway. Whereas existing studies have focused on the temporally imminent coup outcome, I argue that putsch diffusion should focus on vulnerability. Coups exhibit diffusive characteristics through the combination of immediate shocks and historical legacy, of coups in a given neighborhood. Existing innovation diffusion literature has illustrated how spread can be mitigated or exacerbated due to characteristics of the innovation, actors involved, and environment.</description></item><item><title>Them Belly Full but We Hungry</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/food/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/food/</guid><description>Testing Hunger is a ubiquitous force in the annals of political instability. It is a feeling that can lead collectives toward huge social change. Momentous ends to French (1789) and Russian (1917) monarchies were ignited by starvation. Revolutionary change is an easily identifiable form of political instability, but in the modern state system it is very rare. Of the 317 irregular leader changes identified by Archigos dataset, over 200 of those events were coups.</description></item><item><title>Food, Familiarity, and Forecasting: Modeling Coups with Computational Methods</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/abstract/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/dissertation/abstract/</guid><description>The final dissertation is openly available through UCF. In an effort to condense the research to a more approachable format, I have put together a few pages that reflect some of the key arguments and findings.
Abstract Military coups are the most consequential breakdown of civil-military relations. This dissertation contributes to the explanation and prediction of coups through three independent quantitative analyses. First, I argue that food insecurity is an important determinant of coups.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/introduction/</guid><description>I serve as a Postdoctoral Fellow and NLP/Machine Learning Researcher for The University of Central Florida&amp;rsquo;s National Center for Integrated Coastal Research and School of Politics, Security, and International Affairs. I hold a Ph.D. in Security Studies from the University of Central Florida (UCF). Currently my research is focused on quantifying adaptive pathways for coastal systems utilizing advanced computational methods. My dissertation uses spatial and environmental determinants to better predict global coups d&amp;rsquo;etat.</description></item><item><title>A changing State of the Union</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/sotu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/sotu/</guid><description>The State of the Union is an important public moment for every president since Woodrow Wilson set the precedent in 1913. These speeches generate millions of views and are often laundry lists of policy preferences and achievements. Presidents are well aware of the public nature of these speeches and the preparation makes them primed for comparison across offices.
The use of at-a-distance psychological trait analysis creates an opportunity to assess some general SOTU trends.</description></item><item><title>Conflict and Control in Donbass</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/donbass/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/donbass/</guid><description>Conflict I was recently asked by a colleague for some help making an updated map on territorial control in Ukraine. This led me down a rabbit hole.
The conflict itself is almost entirely concentrated in the Donbass region of eastern Ukraine. Since the beginning of 2018 until November 9th, 2019, ACLED has recorded 1,267 fatalities as a result of the conflict. The data source has also recorded 55 unique actors involved.</description></item><item><title>Security Studies Web Data</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/ssweb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/ssweb/</guid><description>Many modern data sources are updated frequently. Working through my dissertation and various research projects, I&amp;rsquo;ve become tired of having to download data to keep the pipeline of analysis up-to-date. While R has a number of libraries that do this contemporaneous data download, python libraries are less available. I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a basic package that does this for a few data sources. I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to a) install the package and b) some basic usage.</description></item><item><title>Election Violence: Latin America</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/election/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/election/</guid><description>Electoral Contention and Violence (EVAC) A key pillar of democratic governance is elections. This represents the time when leadership can change hands. When it does so peacefully this is a sign of a strong and stable government. The need to understand when, where and why acts of violence occur surrounding these outcomes is of great importance. A new dataset produced by Daxecker, Amicarelli and Jung addresses this need.
Although Latin America accounts for only 8% of all events within the EVAC data set, it is interesting to visualize the distribution of these events.</description></item><item><title>Coups: REIGN</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/reign/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/reign/</guid><description>Download A number of data sets exist that record the political phenomenon of coup d&amp;rsquo;etat. I will review how to attain and process each of these data sets in turn before comparing them with respect to data analysis.
In this post I review the Rulers, Elections, and Irregular Governance (REIGN) data set. This data set is produced by Curtis Bell of OneEarthFuture foundation. It is regularly updated and maintains a country-month level of analysis.</description></item><item><title>Mapping the Bayou</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/bayou/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/blog/bayou/</guid><description>Cajun Waterways Southern Louisiana is known for great cooking and a festive lifestyle. A key part of both is the hydrological landscape that shapes the state. Following some inspiration from Näytä Data, I mapped out these systems using the National Hydrogrophy Dataset (NHD).
The Blue represents regions where rivers, lakes and streams are present. Rivers and streams are weighted by the Strahler number which measures the branch significance. To the west of the most important Mississippi river is the Atchafalaya, Red and Black rivers which run parallel.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ``` [outputs] home = [&amp;ldquo;HTML&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo;] ```</description></item></channel></rss>