<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Joshua E. Lambert, PhD</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Joshua E. Lambert, PhD</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://JELambert.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Search Results</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ``` [outputs] home = [&amp;ldquo;HTML&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo;] ```</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/publications/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/publications/</guid><description>Dissertation Food, Familiarity, and Forecasting: Modeling Coups with Computational Methods. PDF Reports and Policy Papers Reassessing Rebellion. One Earth Future, with Eric Keels, Jay Benson, and John Filitz. (PDF)
Fish Wars: The Causes and Consequences of Fisheries Conflict in Tanzania. One Earth Future, with Sarah M. Glaser, Colleen Devlin, Ciera Villegas, and Natasia Poinsatte. (PDF)
Peer Reviewed Reassessing Private Military and Security Company (PMSC) &amp;lsquo;Competition&amp;rsquo; in Civil War: Lessons from Sierra Leone.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/talks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/talks/</guid><description>2021 American Political Science Association Religious Pluralism and Mass Violence: A Global Analysis
with Gunes Tezcur International Studies Association Annual Meeting (Virtual) Militarized Fisheries Conflicts Associated with Global Climate
with Cullen Hendrix, Sarah M. Glaser, and Paige Roberts Centre College Guest Lecture (IST 210 - Research Design) Overview of GIS in Empirical Social Science
UCF School of Politics, Security and International Affairs Colloquium The Commons Synthesis Project: Applying machine learning to synthesize knowledge on community-based natural resource management</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://JELambert.github.io/posts/introduction/</guid><description>I serve as a Postdoctoral Fellow and NLP/Machine Learning Researcher for The University of Central Florida&amp;rsquo;s National Center for Integrated Coastal Research and School of Politics, Security, and International Affairs. I hold a Ph.D. in Security Studies from the University of Central Florida (UCF). Currently my research is focused on quantifying adaptive pathways for coastal systems utilizing advanced computational methods. My dissertation uses spatial and environmental determinants to better predict global coups d&amp;rsquo;etat.</description></item></channel></rss>